14.Write a program to compare two strings without using strcmp() function. strcmp() function compares two strings lexicograp hically. strcmp is declared in stdio.h Case 1: when the strings are equal, it returns zero. Case 2: when the strings are unequal, it returns the difference between ascii values of the characters that differ. a) When string1 is greater than string2, it returns positive value. b) When string1 is lesser than string2, it returns negative value. Syntax: int strcmp (const char *s1, const char *s2); Program: to compare two strings. #include #include int cmpstr(cha r s1[10], char s2[10]); int main(){ char arr1[10] ="Nodalo"; char arr2[10] ="nodalo"; printf("%d", cmpstr(arr 1, arr2)); // cmpstr() is equivalent of strcmp() return 0; }/ /s1, s2 are strings to be compared int cmpstr(cha r s1[10], char s2[10]){ //strlen function returns the length of argument string passed int i = strlen(s1) ; int k = strlen(s2) ; int bigger; if (i<k){ bigger = k; } else if (i>k){ bigger = i; } else{ bigger = i; } //loops'bigger'times for (i = 0; i<bigger; i++){ // if ascii values of characters s1[i], s2[i] are equal do nothing if (s1[i] == s2[i]){ } //else return the ascii difference else{ return (s1[i] - s2[i]); } } //return 0 when both strings are same //This statement is executed only when both strings are equal return (0); } Output: -32 Explanatio n: cmpstr() is a function that illustrate s C standard function strcmp(). Strings to be compared are sent as arguments to cmpstr(). Each character in string1 is compared to its correspond ing character in string2. Once the loop encounters a differing character in the strings, it would return the ascii difference of the differing characters and exit. 15.Write a program