2. Write a program to check whether the given number is even or odd. Program: 

#include int main(){ int a; printf("En ter a: \n"); scanf("%d" ,&a); /* logic */ if (a % 2 == 0){ printf("Th e given number is EVEN\n"); } else{ printf("Th e given number is ODD\n"); } return 0; } Output: Enter a: 2 The given number is EVEN Explanatio n with examples: Example 1: If entered number is an even number Let value of'a'entered is 4 if(a%2==0) then a is an even number, else odd. i.e. if(4%2==0) then 4 is an even number, else odd. To check whether 4 is even or odd, we need to calculate (4%2). /* % (modulus) implies remainder value. */ /* Therefore if the remainder obtained when 4 is divided by 2 is 0, then 4 is even. */ 4%2==0 is true Thus 4 is an even number. Example 2: If entered number is an odd number. Let value of'a'entered is 7 if(a%2==0) then a is an even number, else odd. i.e. if(7%2==0) then 4 is an even number, else odd. To check whether 7 is even or odd, we need to calculate (7%2). 7%2==0 is false /* 7%2==1 condition fails and else part is executed */ Thus 7 is an odd number.