11.Write a program to generate the Fibonacci series.
 Fibonacci series: Any number in the series is obtained by adding the previous two numbers of the series. 
Let f(n) be n'th term.
 f(0)=0; f(1)=1; f(n)=f(n-1 )+f(n-2); 
(for n>=2) 
Series is as follows 011 (1+0) 2 (1+1) 3 (1+2) 5 (2+3) 8 (3+5) 13 (5+8) 21 (8+13) 34 (13+21) ...and so on Program: to generate Fibonacci Series(10 terms) 
#include 
int main()
{
 //array fib stores numbers of fibonacci series
 int i, fib[25]; 
// initialized first element to 0 fib[0] = 0;
 // initialized second element to 1 fib[1] = 1;
 //loop to generate ten elements 
for (i = 2; i<10; i++)
{ 
//i'th element of series is equal to the sum of i-1'th element and i-2'th element. 
fib[i] = fib[i - 1] + fib[i - 2];
 } 
printf("The fibonacci series is as follows \n"); 
//print all numbers in the series
 for (i = 0; i<10; i++)
{ printf("%d \n", fib[i]); 
}
 return 0; 
} 
Output: The fibonacci series is as follows 01123581 3 21 34 
Explanatio n: The first two elements are initialize d to 0, 1 respective ly. Other elements in the series are generated by looping and adding previous two numbes. These numbers are stored in an array and ten elements of the series are printed as output. 12.Write a program