 10.Write a program to check whether the given string is a palindrome . Palindrome is a string, which when read in both forward and backward way is same. Example: radar, madam, pop, lol, rubber, etc., Program: #include #include int main(){ char string1[20 ]; int i, length; int flag = 0; printf("En ter a string: \n"); scanf("%s" , string1); length = strlen(str ing1); for(i=0;i<length ;i++){ if(string1 [i] != string1[le ngth-i-1]) { flag = 1; break; } } if (flag){ printf("%s is not a palindrome \n", string1); } else{ printf("%s is a palindrome \n", string1); } return 0; } Output: Enter a string: radar "radar"is a palindrome Explanatio n with example: To check if a string is a palindrome or not, a string needs to be compared with the reverse of itself. Consider a palindrome string:"radar", ---------- ---------- ------- index: 0 1 2 3 4 value: r a d a r ---------- ---------- ------- To compare it with the reverse of itself, the following logic is used: 0th character in the char array, string1 is same as 4th character in the same string. 1st character is same as 3rd character. 2nd character is same as 2nd character. . . . . ith character is same as'length-i- 1'th character. If any one of the above condition fails, flag is set to true(1), which implies that the string is not a palindrome . By default, the value of flag is false(0). Hence, if all the conditions are satisfied, the string is a palindrome .