8. Write a program to check whether the given number is a prime. A prime number is a natural number that has only one and itself as factors. Examples: 2, 3, 13 are prime numbers. Program: #include main(){ int n, i, c = 0; printf("En ter any number n: \n"); scanf("%d" ,&n); /*logic*/ for (i = 1; i if (n % i == 0){ c++; } } if (c == 2){ printf("n is a Prime number"); } else{ printf("n is not a Prime number"); } return 0; } Output: Enter any number n: 7 n is Prime Explanatio n with examples: consider a number n=5 for(i=0;i i.e. for(i=0;i 1st iteration: i=1;i here i is incremente d i.e. i value for next iteration is 2 now if(n%i==0) then c is incremente d i.e.if(5%1 ==0)then c is incremente d, here 5%1=0 thus c is incremente d. now c=1; 2nd iteration: i=2;i here i is incremente d i.e. i value for next iteration is 3 now if(n%i==0) then c is incremente d i.e.if(5%2 ==0) then c is incremente d, but 5%2!=0 and so c is not incremente d, c remains 1 c=1; 3rd iteration: i=3;i here i is incremente d i.e. i value for next iteration is 4 now if(n%i==0) then c is incremente d i.e.if(5%3 ==0) then c ic incremente d, but 5%3!=0 and so c is not incremente d, c remains 1 c=1; 4th iteration: i=4;i here i is incremente d i.e. i value for next iteration is 5 now if(n%i==0) then c is incremente d i.e. if(5%4==0) then c is incremente d, but 5%4!=0 and so c is not incremente d, c remains 1 c=1; 5th iteration: i=5;i here i is incremente d i.e. i value for next iteration is 6 now if(n%i==0) then c is incremente d i.e. if(5%5==0) then c is incremente d, 5%5=0 and so c is incremente d. i.e. c=2 6th iteration: i=6;i here i value is 6 and 6 now if(c==2) then n is a prime number we have c=2 from the 5th iteration and thus n=5 is a Prime number.