rints the string "Hello World". 13.Write a program to print a semicolon without using a semicolon anywhere in the code. Generally when use printf("") statement we have to use semicolon at the end. If we want to print a semicolon, we use the statement: printf(";" ); In above statement, we are using two semicolons . The task of printing a semicolon without using semicolon anywhere in the code can be accomplish ed by using the ascii value of';'which is equal to 59. Program: Program to print a semicolon without using semicolon in the code. #include int main(void) { //prints the character with ascii value 59, i.e., semicolon if (printf("% c\n", 59)){ //prints semicolon } return 0; } Output: ; Explanatio n: If statement checks whether return value of printf function is greater than zero or not. The return value of function call printf("%c ",59) is 1. As printf returns the length of the string printed. printf ("%c ",59) prints ascii value that correspond s to 59, that is semicolon( .