rn Programming Swapping two integers in a one liner I found some really cool one liner solutions to swap two integers without using a temporary variable. Some of them are listed here : 1. a+=b-=a=b-a; 2. a/=b=(a=a*b)/b; 3. a^=b^=a^=b; same as a=(b=(a=b^a)^b) ^a; 4. b=a+b-(a=b); Each individually are cool solutions. But all of them have one big problem. These are not portable! C standard says that when a value of an operand is changed in the same expression at some other place, then the result of the expression is undefined. Try running the program on gcc with -Wall option. All the above one liners (which are really cool to begin with!) are plagued by that.So I feel the most portable way to achieve the goal is: a = a xor b; b = a xor b; a = a xor b; Unfortunately it is not a one liner.